A Guide to the Papers of Zelda J. Miller 1950s-1960s
Special Collections, Perry Library, Old Dominion University
Special Collections, Perry Library, Old Dominion University
The Papers of Zelda J. Miller 1950s-1960s
Special Collections, Perry Library, Old Dominion University
MG 73
3 Hollinger Document Cases.
Administrative Information
Access
Available to researchers without restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift from Peter Stewart.
Biographical/Historical Information
Zelda J. Miller was a teacher at Robert E. Lee School in Norfolk, Virginia during the 1950s and 1960s.
Scope and Content Information
The material in this collection dates from the 1950s and 1960s. The material consists entirely of historical and civic information about the Hampton Roads area, historical figures, and local industries. A particular emphasis is on the Virginia colonies and early settlers. This collection includes course materials, newspaper and magazine articles, maps, photos, booklets, and pamphlets.
Arrangement
Arrangement
This collection is arranged alphabetically by name of person, place, or subject.
Organization
This collection is broken down into the following series: I. Places, II. People, and III. Other Topics.
Series I: Places. This series contains information mainly about the Tidewater area of Virginia and Norfolk, in particular. Places include Cape Henry, Jamestown, Newport News, Norfolk, and the State of Virginia. Topics include historical places, museums, and events of interest; the colonies and early settlers to Virginia; historical events, and government. Of particular note is the information on the Norfolk's historic Mace. Norfolk is the only city in the United States that has had a complete silver Mace in its possession since Colonial Days.
Series II: People. This series includes information on people of historic significance. Included are Thomas Alva Edison, Thomas Jefferson, Ponce de Leon, Abraham Lincoln, and George Washington.
Series III: Other Topics. This series includes material on other topics in the collection, and miscellaneous items. It includes information on fisheries, seafood, and other Virginia industries; historic churches; music in Norfolk public schools; miscellaneous newspaper articles; and other miscellaneous items. Of particular note are two children's educational comic books from the 1950s located in the Fisheries, Seafood, and Industries folder. "Chocolate - The Flavor of Friendship Around the World: The Story of Nestle's - From Cocoa Bean to Chocolate Bar" and "The Personal Story of Mr. Peanut" are well worth the reading.
Contents List
- Places
  - Cape Henry (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Jamestown I (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Jamestown II (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Lynchburg-The Young Virginian, 1957-1958 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Newport News-War Memorial Museum (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Norfolk-Azalea Festival (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Norfolk-City Council (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Norfolk-Glimpses of Ghent (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Norfolk-Guides and Pamphlets (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Norfolk Mace and Seal (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Norfolk Magazine, 1951 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Norfolk Magazine, 1953-1955 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Norfolk Magazine, 1957-1958 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Norfolk-Portsmouth Maps (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Norfolk Museums (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Norfolk Ports (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 16)
  - The Norfolk Story, 1948, 1951, 1956, 1957, 1960, 1963 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 1)
  - The Story of the Norfolk Pageant (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Stories of Norfolk, Part One & Part Two (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Norfolk is Our City, Part One & Part Two (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 4)
  - North Carolina-The Lost Colony (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Tidewater Virginia in Years Gone By (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Tidewater Virginia Mural (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 7)
  - The United States (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Virginia-The Commonwealth Magazine 1954 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Virginia Crops and Livestock (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Virginia Drawings (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Virginia Guides (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Virginia-Natural Resources (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Virginia: "Open These Gates to the Land of Romance" (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Virginia-Other Cities (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Williamsburg (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 16)
- People
  - Thomas Alva Edison (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Thomas Jefferson (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Ponce de Leon (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Abraham Lincoln (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 4)
  - George Washington (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 5)
  - U.S. Presidents (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 6)
- Other Topics
  - Fisheries, Seafood, and Industry (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Historic Churches (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Music (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Perry Library Online Catalog Search (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous Newspaper Articles (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 12)